<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Anson Kao]]></title><description><![CDATA[Entrepreneur, Engineer, Creator]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 19:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[I made a Lifetime Commitment to Never Fart in Front of my Significant Other, and You Should Too]]></title><description><![CDATA[A pretty common but controversial conversation amongst couples is this question of “How soon is too soon to start farting in front of your…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/i-made-a-lifetime-commitment-to-never-fart-in-front-of-my-significant-other-and-you-should-too/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/i-made-a-lifetime-commitment-to-never-fart-in-front-of-my-significant-other-and-you-should-too/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;A pretty common but controversial conversation amongst couples is this question of “How soon is too soon to start farting in front of your significant other?” Is 6 months too soon? 12 months? Not until you’re married or moved in together? Only on days you didn’t eat eggs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, one thing that’s always frustrated me about this question is that it assumes one thing: that it SHOULD &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; be acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what I think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s fucking BULLSHIT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me explain why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/8856/0*mS5Ydm5ThKriHj77&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by Timo Stern on Unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would you ever fart on your first date with someone? No. Why? Because you want impress them, to make a good first impression on them, right? To appear sexy to them, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, let me ask you this. Do you no longer want to impress your significant/other, your wife or husband? Is it no longer necessary to appear sexy to them, because you’ve been with them “long enough?” Well, this is my answer: HELL NO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to be sexy to my significant other forever. I don’t think farting is sexy, so until the day I die, I’m holding that shit in (forgive the pun). I do think puns are sexy, however, so those I let loose 😏.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I accidentally fart in my sleep, at least it’s a funny accident and we can laugh about it. But that version of the future where we just let farts loose mid-conversation and it’s no big deal and we just accept it as life? Because we’re “comfortable”? Screw that. That’s complacent. That’s my nightmare come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Don’t be complacent.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep dating your significant other. Keep being sexy, whatever your definition of sexy may be — forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;🕺&lt;/h2&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2 months ago, I started meditating everyday. Here’s why]]></title><description><![CDATA[Because I follow a lot of Silicon Valley folks on Twitter and it seems like the cool thing to — JUST KIDDING! 🤣 It all started because of a…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/2-months-ago-i-started-meditating-everyday-heres-why/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/2-months-ago-i-started-meditating-everyday-heres-why/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Because I follow a lot of Silicon Valley folks on Twitter and it seems like the cool thing to — JUST KIDDING! 🤣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It all started because of a fight I had with my girlfriend.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;“Meditation is for losers”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think meditation was this mystical thing that you could only do if you quit your job and fled to India to devote your life to becoming a monk. I knew a few people that were interested in it, but instead of taking the chance to participate with them and learn together, I silently judged them. “Hippies, all of you! Get a fucking job and do something productive… &lt;strong&gt;spits&lt;/strong&gt;” 😒&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My good friend Dien changed that for me in July of 2017. We had gone on a trip to Utah/Arizona together. He and I were both soul-searching and we took our questions about life to the great sandstone parks: Zion, Bryce, Horseshoe Bend, Antelope Valley, Grand Canyon. This is one of my favourite destinations in the world and I intend to return many times in my life. Aside from some powerful revelations we had there (which needs its own post), the canyons were a brilliant environment for meditation and it didn’t take a devotee to realize that. Dien lead a couple guided sessions with me, and we captured this time lapse of us in the Grand Canyon:&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_Z9rC9e2E4k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;p&gt;From this experience, I now knew the basic mechanics of meditation, and the practice was now a little less foreign / a little more approachable. So after we got back from that trip, I tried tried using Calm.com / Headspace for a few minutes each day to keep the ball rolling. Focus on your breath, become aware of your body, and relax; seems simple enough, right? Sadly though, I gave up after a few attempts, because I still didn’t REALLY get why I was doing it. If I want to relax, why don’t I just take a nap or watch something funny? 🤷‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fast forward to 3 months ago (2 years later)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got into a brutal fight with my girlfriend 😱🥵. The exact details of the fight could be it’s own post, so I’ll just summarize my takeaways from the fight like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;I need to figure out how to be less stubborn. I have to do this quickly (a) if I want to succeed in business and (b) if I want my relationship to feel more like paradise than like prison.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a really, really bad fight. Tears were shed. I felt demoralized and scared for my own future, and for my girlfriend’s as well. But I was determined to do something about it, so I did what any reasonable human being would do in this day and age: I googled &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to become less stubborn”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and stayed up late crawling down the rabbit hole. The quality of the search results were not the greatest: a lot of Yahoo! Answers, listicles, and emotional ranting on various social networks (but I will concede that there was no porn 🤣). In my desperation, I even emailed a few of the spiritually inclined (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; hippie &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;) people I found. Was this a new low in my life? 😖&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, two things happened in the weeks that followed that felt like striking gold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading an e-book called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ZJZbv4J6FZ8Dnb0JuMhJxTnwl-dwqx5xl0s65DE3wO8/edit&quot;&gt;The Great CEO Within&lt;/a&gt;” by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mattmochary&quot;&gt;Matt Mochary&lt;/a&gt;. This book basically catalogues and humanizes the various challenges that successful entrepreneurs go through. Turns out stubbornness is a very common challenge, even amongst (perhaps &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; amongst) the greatest leaders. So much so, that this topic has its own separate book called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.ca/15-Commitments-Conscious-Leadership-Sustainable/dp/0990976904/&quot;&gt;The 15 Commitments of the Conscious Leadership&lt;/a&gt;” listed in the Further Reading section. I immediately bought it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The random dude that I emailed responded, with a 5000 character essay. WOW! I’ve been keeping in touch with him since, exchanging a few emails here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you guess what both the books and my new pen pal pointed me to as the solution for stubbornness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meditation is the antidote&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I understood why I need to meditate. It’s not about relaxing — it’s about TRAINING. Teaching your mind to handle things differently, and developing a stronger mental self-awareness. Furthermore, stubbornness is just the mind handling new information poorly. So, meditation is the perfect approach with which to tackle stubbornness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out this is a journey I’ve already been on for several years, just in a passive way where I would observe my own misgivings with no way to convert the feedback into something actionable. Now, armed with meditation, I have a way to push forward deliberately and on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What does success look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only became clear to me that meditation really is the solution when I saw it described this way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;You can’t prevent a thought or emotion from appearing in your head. But you can learn to shift away from it faster.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, that “saint” we all admire — that one person every group of friends has that just somehow always seems calm — they still have unwieldy thoughts. They just get past them WAY faster than the rest of us. That’s what I want for myself, in business, in romance, and in all aspects of life — to get past my emotions faster, and make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So I made a lifetime commitment to daily meditation.&lt;/strong&gt; In August, I meditated 5 minutes every morning. In September, I increased it to 10 minutes. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Armed with this new motivation to be a better leader, I was now able to get past the mental hurdles that I had with meditation 2 years ago and stick to the routine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still very early on in this journey, and it’s hard to measure progress objectively. But I am already finding some signs of improvement with how I handle emotions. Instead of getting triggered by something and acting dismissive to people for hours, I’m now calling myself out within a few minutes. With time, that recovery period will be down to 5 seconds &lt;em&gt;#superpowers⚡&lt;/em&gt;️.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2240/1*-76K6-vIkHC6bR0sMMGZ7A.png&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Meditating in the Grand Canyon&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shoutouts 🙏&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Dien, who just got back from a 10-day Vipassana retreat today: thanks for your leadership in this all, gonna be leaning on you more for this &lt;em&gt;#brainsurgery&lt;/em&gt;. To Erdal, for love that’s so strong it transcends international waters. And thank you Amy, &lt;em&gt;#bestgirlfriendever&lt;/em&gt;, for putting up with my antics! 👻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;️ 🧘‍♂️&lt;/h2&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[noun: Perfection]]></title><description><![CDATA[About 20 years ago, Amel Larrieux wrote what I still believe to this day is the most endearing love song of all time: “Make Me Whole…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/noun-perfection/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/noun-perfection/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;About 20 years ago, Amel Larrieux wrote what I still believe to this day is the most endearing love song of all time: “Make Me Whole.”&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZbfY18eb3C8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;p&gt;Perfection — it is one of those things that never &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; happens. Life is like a winding path; it ebbs and flows, like a see saw, only being at hypothetical balance for what may appear to be an infinitesimally small moment in time. Perfection feels unattainable, yet the endless pursuit that follows it is always a worth living for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If perfection could ever be captured in a bottle, this song is it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*Za-qRAfQRqmqCBBBjXaMmg.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;“Infinite Possibilities” — Album Art&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The job every aspiring Technical Founder should try]]></title><description><![CDATA[After my second startup failed in 2016, I found myself doing something I never thought I’d do — taking a full-time job. You have to…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-job-every-aspiring-technical-founder-should-try/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-job-every-aspiring-technical-founder-should-try/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After my second startup failed in 2016, I found myself doing something I never thought I’d do — taking a full-time job. You have to understand, I’d spent all of my entire professional career up until that point working exclusively in the startup world — much of it as my own boss (and determined to keep it that way) — and so getting this job felt a bit like I was admitting defeat in some way. But after over a year in my current role, I’m happy to conclude that this has been a really good move for me. So much so, that I’d like to share the following recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;If you are an aspiring technical founder, you should consider spending some time as a Solutions Architect at an &lt;strong&gt;agency-side company&lt;/strong&gt; before you do your next startup.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain my recommendation, first, let’s dive into the most common mistake that technical founders make when building a company. Then, I’ll elaborate on how you can double-down on lessons learned with this recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Technical Founder’s Achilles Heel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the most common mistake technical founders make is this: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;they over-index on writing code, and forget to do “everything else”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I was guilty of this in 2016, and many incredibly intelligent founders I know in the Toronto ecosystem are guilty of it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/10368/0*sLiBjWL0iCTTaJ9h&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;When I should’ve spent an hour evaluating my progress and figuring out if/how I need to need to adjust my plan, instead I just spent that hour writing more code. When I should’ve spent an hour talking to customers and understanding if I was actually solving their problems, instead I just spent that hour writing more code.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a solo technical founder, the ratio should be something like 20% writing code to 80% other activities, instead of the other way around. Remember, the goal of starting a business is not to build shit. The goal of starting a business is to create a profitable feedback loop between providing a product/service and getting paid by customers. And that takes a lot of planning, conversation, and course correction. Yes, one of your Herculean tasks is to get shit built, but the “coding” aspect is actually just a small portion of what it takes to assemble that profitable feedback loop. As a founder, you must have ownership over the entire process — not just the writing code part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t done your first startup yet, you might not see it, but the symptom I described above is a very real problem that all technical founders are susceptible to. Sometimes writing code is just more fun. Sometimes, we simply lack the experience to know there is a better way. Sometimes, we know but just forget, because our egos get in the way of using our time wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, if you’ve already done a startup, maybe you can already relate to the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, avoiding these traps is a muscle that you can practice. If this resonates with you, please read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Growth Opportunity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s break down my recommendation and how it will benefit you as an technical person in the business world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;If you are an aspiring technical founder, you should consider spending some time as a &lt;strong&gt;Solutions Architect&lt;/strong&gt; at an agency-side company before you do your next startup.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two key aspects to this recommendation: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Solutions Architect”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Agency-side company.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. The role: Solutions Architect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is pretty much a role where you do all of the things that a software engineer might ever do, &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; for the writing code part. You spend your time gathering technical requirements, identifying an architectural solution to fulfill those needs, helping sell the client on it contractually, and finally guiding an engineering team through building that solution architecture. Basically, you do all of the planning, and none of the coding. In this role, you get &lt;em&gt;really good&lt;/em&gt; at planning and oversight. Some profound lessons I’ve personally learned are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thinking about software in terms of RISK.&lt;/strong&gt; As an aspiring entrepreneur, it is tempting to drink the coolaid of unending optimism. But while optimism is a necessary ingredient to creating something new, it must be grounded in reality. That’s where risk comes in. Instead of thinking “how quickly could I build X?”, thinking in terms of risk leads us to ask “which part of this project is most likely to cause me trouble?” The former is ego-driven and often leads to unrealistic expectations and missed deadlines. The latter is a tougher question to ask but often leads to better outcomes. Think “professional paranoia.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The cost of taking shortcuts.&lt;/strong&gt; When you are a lone-wolf writing code in a scrappy startup environment, it’s easy to take shortcuts, skip certain planning phases, and make up for them later on your own time. In truth, this is sometimes necessary to make shit happen. However, do you really know what price you’re paying by taking those shortcuts? As a solutions architect, when you take a shortcut in planning, it is usually multiple other people in the engineering team that pays the price. This incentivizes you towards good planning, rather than towards spending more time writing code. It teaches a higher level of awareness over what the critical path really is, and what price the entire project actually pays when you make these compromises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some companies, this role is referred to as “Technical PM”, but at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.symbilitysolutions.com/symbility-intersect/&quot;&gt;Symbility Intersect&lt;/a&gt; where I’m in the role, it’s called “Solutions Architect”. &lt;em&gt;At the time of writing, the team is actually hiring, so if you’re interested, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.symbilitysolutions.com/symbility-intersect/careers/#current-openings&quot;&gt;openings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Type of company: Agency-Side&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot entrepreneurs subscribe to the idea that they should always be working for a startup — whether it’s one that they founded themselves, or by someone else. I know, because that was me too. And if it’s not a startup, it has to be a product company. It makes sense — surround yourself with like-minded people, right? Yes, but to a degree — it can be counterproductive to over-index to polar extremes. Consider these benefits of spending some of your time at a well-established &lt;em&gt;agency-side&lt;/em&gt; company (e.g. a “dev-shop” or “consultancy”):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Process. *&lt;em&gt;If you spend too many years in small and scrappy startups, you’ll never experience good process, and you’ll never know how big of a difference it can make. Agency-side companies are *especially&lt;/em&gt; good at this, because they have to spin up teams very quickly to fill client needs, and teams can only be spun up quickly if you have tight processes on lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration.&lt;/strong&gt; At product companies, it is commonplace for software developers go years on a single project with the same team, without being exposed to anything different. On the other hand, because software agencies go through so many different projects, typically with a different team each time, you get to iterate in a way that isn’t possible in a product company. At Symbility Intersect, I’ve been on almost 10 projects in the past year and a half. With each of those projects, I got to experience working with different teams of different configurations, try new approaches to process, and learn the lessons from when things go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an aspiring technical founder, and you want to do a startup — stop over-indexing on the “building shit” + “optimism” formula, and get good at planning and process first. You can do that as a Solutions Architect. And if you want to learn fast, an agency-side company is a great option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;P.S. So Anson, is this your way of telling us you’re starting another company?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, not quite yet. But I am &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more prepared to start one today than I was 3 years ago. I have more to say on this topic, but I‘ll save it for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🙌 Thanks for reading! 🙌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to be the world’s best magician]]></title><description><![CDATA[Most people know who David Blaine is, but if you don’t — checkout  him out . He is sometimes credited with being the magician that brought…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/how-to-be-the-worlds-best-magician/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/how-to-be-the-worlds-best-magician/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Most people know who David Blaine is, but if you don’t — checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z8Ws4PEky28&quot;&gt;him out&lt;/a&gt;. He is sometimes credited with being the magician that brought street magic, or 1-on-1 performance, to popularity. He also is an “endurance artist” — doing incredible feats such as staying under water for a week or not eating for 44 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*YGAYKX8ieCiuvHeimR_alg.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;David Blaine, Magician and “Endurance Artist”&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Blaine does a TED Talk where he explains his journey to breaking a world record by holding his breath for 17 minutes and 4 seconds. The talk is from 2013 but I just recently discovered it, and there are some brilliant takeaways from it.&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XFnGhrC_3Gs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;p&gt;If you make it to the end of the video, he starts crying and you realize that this isn’t a TED Talk about how to hold your breath. It’s a TED Talk about wanting something really badly, and spending every waking moment of your existence since you were a child making incredible sacrifices in pursuit of absolute perfection of your craft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every morning, this is for months, I would wake up and the first thing that I would do is I would hold my breath…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;— David Blaine, in his TED Talk&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ain’t no bloke that just wanders the streets aimlessly with a deck of cards. He pushed himself religiously towards his goal of being the world’s best magician, and regardless of whether or not you agree he can claim that title, he deserves every single ounce of success he’s attained. This is a powerful message to today’s aspiring entrepreneurs, entertainers, athletes, and academics — you truly, truly have to want something badly, if you’re going to succeed on the world stage. To a fault, even, as if you are a prisoner of your own passion. As if it simply isn’t possible that you don’t succeed. Even if you’re not trying to break the world record for holding your breath, sometimes it may feel like you are holding your breath for months or even years at a time. But you will gladly do it. Cause you simply can’t help yourself. That’s how badly you have to want it. And if you don’t want it that badly, someone else will want it more and take it all away from you. This is what David Blaine’s talk is really about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Blaine. I. Am. In. Awe.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The PRK Recovery Experience]]></title><description><![CDATA[I did PRK laser eye surgery on September 24th, 2015, at Bochner Eye Institute in Toronto. In this blog post, I’ll document what I’ve…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-prk-recovery-experience/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-prk-recovery-experience/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I did PRK laser eye surgery on September 24th, 2015, at Bochner Eye Institute in Toronto. In this blog post, I’ll document what I’ve discovered. Hope it helps someone out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why PRK and not LASIK?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to know about PRK is that the recovery process for it is &lt;em&gt;much, much&lt;/em&gt; longer than LASIK. So why the hell would anyone choose it?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*r4ZrKJQ_hi_WFpZz.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;PRK vs LASIK&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PRK is actually the “original” LASIK. It’s very straightforward — shave off some thickness from the surface of your cornea to correct the refraction of light into your eye. The problem is that it’ll take several months to regrow the surface of your cornea a.k.a. the epithelial layer of the eye. LASIK was invented specifically as a way to eliminate this lengthy healing process. By cutting a thin flap in the cornea, the thickness can be shaved from beneath, and no need to regrow the epithelial layer! Unfortunately, LASIK doesn’t work for a lot of people because there is not always enough thickness in the cornea for both (a) the flap and (b) the corrective shaving. And thus, PRK remains a staple in the laser vision correction industry despite the obvious advantages of LASIK. Okay, so if you have a bad prescription and/or thin corneas, your doctor may have recommended PRK to you. So, how bad is the recovery for it, really? Should you do it? Keep reading below to get the full picture. The explanations that even the best surgeons give are incomplete and there is no substitute for a full length testimonial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 1 — The Surgery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that the surgery was actually very entertaining! It’s kinda like your eyes are going through a car wash. After popping a Valium, you relax and just lay on your back while the surgeon does everything. Thanks to plenty of freezing drops, you can’t even tell when the surgeon touches your eye — you just watch it all unfold like a movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*wGABMb33TZ3SCcXd.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Part of the laser eye surgery experience feels like your eyes are being buffed, kinda like your car’s waxing job.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She starts the surgery by clamping your eyelids open. Every 30 seconds or so she’ll spray some water on your eye to keep it moist. She uses this polishing tool to rub the epithelial layer off (much like a buffer for your car’s waxing job, shown to the right). More water spray. Then before you can blink, the laser correction is done. Really fast — maybe 20 seconds. You can’t even see it happen, and how could you — if you could see the laser that would mean it’s cutting your retina, not your cornea. She now squeegies your eye to remove any debris from the laser. More water spray. Apply bandage contact lense. Remove the clamps. Done. Next eye. After both eyes are complete, you sit in the waiting room just long enough to make sure you feel okay and for a quick checkup with the doctor. When all is well, you’re free to go until the next checkup!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*_FVCvIzEg8QkAh12.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Me with Dr. Cheskes, immediately after the surgery&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, my surgeon was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bochner.com/surgeons_albertcheskes.php&quot;&gt;Dr. Albert Cheskes&lt;/a&gt;, who is great. We even took a glamour shot outside the operating room right after the surgery was complete!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 2 — Regrowing the epithelial layer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same day of the surgery, I didn’t experience any pain. In fact, on the way home from the clinic, I was comfortable enough to drop by the grocery store with my girlfriend to stock up on snacks. There was a haziness over my vision, but I was able to read text at all distances, which felt great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only on the evening of the next day that I started to experience pain. The reason for the pain is that the cells in your epithelial layer are slowly replicating and spreading back over your cornea. As the cells grip onto your cornea, it’s kinda like your eye is literally poking itself. This was really painful, very similar to the stinging feeling you get when cutting open onions in the kitchen or perhaps getting pepper sprayed, except it doesn’t go away for maybe 48 hours. There’s no way around it — just take the pain killers provided, try to sleep it off. Think of it like the muscle soreness/pain in the days after a workout — no pain, no gain. Visualizing the surface of my eye being healed back to normal definitely helped me get through it. By the morning of day 4, the pain had mostly subsided. I would experience only occasional stings throughout the rest of the day (presumably, the last few cracks in my epithelial layer being filled in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 5 — Learning to live away from the keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By day 5, it was pretty obvious that the epithelial layer had regrown. It seems like the surgeons have figured out that it usually heals within 5 days, because they had prescheduled my followup appointment for day 5. When I got to the clinic, the surgeon took out my bandage contact lenses. We did a quick look at the Snellen chart, and I was able to distinguish characters on the 20/40 line, but not without a some real difficulty which I’ll explain below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as the pain had subsided on day 4, I started paying close attention to how well I was seeing. By looking at very distinct shapes, such as the time on an LED clock, it was easy to determine exactly what was happening with my visual acuity. Since I’m a photoshop wiz, I made some mockups so you can see for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*plzoazdsgxxgAAWf.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;My self-visualization of what my ghosting looked like&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shown is a pretty close approximation to what I was seeing with my right eye. As you can see, there’s double vision, which makes it very hard to read text without getting a headache. My left eye has the same amount of ghosting but without the double vision, which makes reading bearable. Presumably the double vision is because of a line that formed in the surface of the right eye. I’m praying that this problem will smooth over sooner rather than later, because it makes it very difficult to get anything productive done without getting a serious headache.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this first week and possible through to the second week, you will most likely not be able to read or watch anything. Make sure you’ve prepared some audiobooks, stand-up comedy, or podcasts to tide you over until week 2. As a creator myself, I was INCREDIBLY bored during this first week. There’s only so much you can listen to before you feel like a prisoner in your own home. Just remember it’ll be worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 9 — Smoothing the epithelial layer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day 9, I woke up to find that the double vision in my right eye has finally disappeared!! Just some directionally ambiguous hazing, but this is MUCH more bearable than the ghosting. The funny thing is, I think it’s because I rubbed my eye the night before. One of the rules of laser eye surgery is that you must avoid rubbing your eyes at ALL COSTS for the first month. Tough luck with that! But I think rubbing my eye helped to smooth out the crack in surface of my right eye that caused the ghosting. How funny is that? I can tell the surgeons weren’t joking though — my right eye has gone back to feeling the way it felt on day 4, just after the pain subsided. Feels a bit raw again. Not gonna rub my eyes again, but I’m really happy with how this accident turned out, lol!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a note that prior to today, focusing on the computer screen has been too frustrating for me to do anything more than a couple hours of work before getting a headache. So if you’re a computer programmer like I am or something similar where you are sitting at the screen all day, be prepared for the possibility that you might have to take a second week off work. I know, it’s not cool — but remember it’ll be worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second week, I ended up reducing the resolution of my computer monitors so that everything gets bigger, and that made it possible for me to be productive with anything except programming. I was forced to find ways to be productive without programming, e.g. getting as many of my errands out of the way as possible, and working on some presentation or design work that I had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 20 — Final touches to the epithelial layer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day 20, I realized that my ability to distance vision for street signs had gotten quite clear, so I reverted my computer monitor resolution back to normal, and to my surprise I was able to get by. I had to sit a bit closer to the monitor because there was still minor ghosting, but I could manage and be completely productive again. Thank goodness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, there are still quite a bit of starbursts and glowing halos around lights, but it’s not too far off from what I experienced wearing contacts in the past. At this point, I am quite happy with the results and it’s clear to me now that the vision will reach 100% clarity in a few more weeks. I have to admit I was a bit worried that one eye would have better results than the other, which leads to one eye being dominant and and a very imbalanced feeling. In fact, the first few weeks were like this, with the left eye being dominant due to the double vision in the right eye. When the double vision went away, the right eye became dominant as there was actually still more ghosting in the left eye. And now, it seems that the ghosting has tapered off quite well in both eyes, leaving me with balanced vision. Wooot!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 28 — One Month, focusing on distance vision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is my 4 week mark. I’ve been working at full capacity for the past week, but just need to sit a bit closer to the computer screen in order to get past the ghosting. Really happy about that, since I’m a programmer lol. However, now I’m paying more attention to my distance vision, and it seems like my left eye has gone back to being the dominant eye. If I close it, I can see some slight double vision in my right eye in the far distance. So it feels like my right eye has gotten worse, but it might just be my left eye getting there faster and my expectations rising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Flarex steroid drops go down to a 2 drops per eye per day now. I’ve read in other blogs that the improvement really becomes profound after you stop taking the steroid drops — but my surgeon insists I follow his schedule until the 8 week mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Month 2 — “Forgetting” and Beyond&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: March 7th, 2016. Was reminded that I need to update this blog post by a comment notification from Emily below. It’s been half a year, and for the past few months I’ve completely forgotten about my past life where glasses and contacts were a concern. I guess it first occurred to me around the 2 month mark that I could go several days without thinking about the surgery and that I was fully recovered! It’s a pretty freakin awesome feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is my vision today? I’m very satisfied — no glasses/contacts, no dry eyes (except when I first wake up in the morning), and no more hesitations to go about my regular day life. But, if I HAD to complain about one thing, it’s that my right eye never fully caught up to my left eye — it still sees slightly worse. It’s not noticeable when I’m working up close or outside in the brightness of the sun, but it is a bit bothersome when I am in a modestly-lit + far distance situation (such as looking at price signs in a grocery store). In those situations, my right eye sees the numbers ever so slightly blurrier, and it’s a bit annoying. However, if your eyes were as bad as mine before the surgery, this is not nearly as bad as what we were used to from before with glasses getting foggy/sliding down your nose etc. My surgeon and I agree that it’s not worth it to do a touch-up surgery, as I am mostly happy with the result, but should I decide I want it, he’ll do it for free (with no time limit). So make sure you find a surgeon that has lifetime guarantee as part of their policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s it, the end of my story. I’m 99% satisfied, and just going to go on with my life now. Hope this helped someone out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!
Anson 😃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;See Also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found these testimonials from other people really helpful when I was researching PRK:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.freakingawesome.net/my-prk-adventure/&quot;&gt;http://blog.freakingawesome.net/my-prk-adventure/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nogodsallowed.wordpress.com/my-prk-adventure/&quot;&gt;http://nogodsallowed.wordpress.com/my-prk-adventure/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bpheffnerprk.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;http://bpheffnerprk.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brianstucki.com/blog/my-prk-surgery-and-recovery/&quot;&gt;http://www.brianstucki.com/blog/my-prk-surgery-and-recovery/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.expandingknowledge.com/Jerome/HumanBody/Eye/VisionCorrection/LaserSurgery/PRK_MyExperience/Main.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.expandingknowledge.com/Jerome/HumanBody/Eye/VisionCorrection/LaserSurgery/PRK_MyExperience/Main.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alextran.org/my-prk-recovery-timeline/&quot;&gt;http://alextran.org/my-prk-recovery-timeline/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How a Rabbit Changed the Way I Look at People]]></title><description><![CDATA[My girlfriend has a pet rabbit named Momo, and he’s absolutely adorable. Momo the rabbit Did you know that bunnies wipe their faces every…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/how-a-rabbit-changed-the-way-i-look-at-people/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/how-a-rabbit-changed-the-way-i-look-at-people/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My girlfriend has a pet rabbit named Momo, and he’s absolutely adorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/4096/1*3ej0O8nxYQy_p1orVyoYTA.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Momo the rabbit&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that bunnies wipe their faces every 5 minutes? They have all these random idiosyncrasies that are incredibly entertaining to watch, especially when you don’t have a clue what the hell they’re trying to do. For example, Momo has a tendency to bite thin objects he finds around the house, like my shoelaces or my iPhone cable. His teeth are sharp, so he manages to take solid chunks out of the insulation. But he never completely cuts the cable — he just bites it, gets bored, and leaves. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another amusing behaviour of Momo is when he scratches things. Recently, he started scratching this one corner of the ground by the bed. He just goes there and starts scratching, like he’s trying to dig a hole through to China. I found this very hilarious, until my girlfriend pointed out that it’s a common behaviour for wild rabbits to dig holes as some sorta survival mechanism. Then my inquisitive side took over and I got to thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

          &lt;div
            class=&quot;gatsby-resp-iframe-wrapper&quot;
            style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; height: 0; overflow: hidden;margin-bottom: 1.0725rem&quot;
          &gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3-n7i24g8Ks&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;
            position: absolute;
            top: 0;
            left: 0;
            width: 100%;
            height: 100%;
          &quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          
&lt;p&gt;How did Momo learn these behaviours? Momo is not a wild rabbit, and unlike dogs or cats, he never gets to learn from other rabbits at the park. Momo is Tarzan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more I observed him, the more I realized that his father dug holes too, and his grandfather before him. If Momo had a son, he too, would instinctively dig holes. We could breed his lineage for a thousand generations and as domesticated rabbits the urge to dig holes would simply never disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried to see if we could get him to stop digging. We blocked the area you see Momo digging at in the video with some really difficult obstacles, like a yoga mat that was firmly pressed into the crevice of the bed frame. I would catch him in the middle of the night, yanking relentlessly on the corner of the mat with his teeth. If Momo has the ability to think rationally, he is not using it when he digs. These random idiosyncrasies he has, they are raw, animal instincts, and they simply cannot be reasoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I wondered, who was the first rabbit that ever dug a hole? And I realized that there isn’t much difference between a behaviour that is driven by animal instinct, and a behaviour that is driven by something like a childhood fear. When a thought is reinforced thousands of times in one’s mind by reliving an emotional experience, it develops into an instinct, and if strong enough, this behaviour can be passed onto others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads me to my main message regarding people and how we deal with each other: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;we need to stop judging&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Because sometimes, people don’t have a choice — we are wired by our past to behave a certain way, and it is shortsighted to expect us to see things differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;em&gt;The worst thing to call somebody is crazy. It’s dismissive. “I don’t understand this person. So they’re crazy.” That’s bullshit. These people are not crazy. They strong people. Maybe their environment is a little sick.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;em&gt;— Dave Chappelle, on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0850928/&quot;&gt;Inside the Actor’s Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next time you catch yourself about to judge someone with tattoos, piercings, saggy pants, plastic surgery, drug addictions, or &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; that’s not normal to you, I urge you to first think about why that someone is behaving that way. No-one is trying intentionally to be strange or inferior. We are all just doing the best we can with what we were given, genetically or otherwise. Just like Momo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if someone can explain to me why Momo likes chewing my cables, please do so in the comments because I can’t for the life of me figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The iTunes Model is Already Obsolete]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s take a look at the past to understand the evolution of music sales and how iTunes fits in today. In the days of vinyl and compact…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-itunes-model-is-already-obsolete/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/the-itunes-model-is-already-obsolete/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the past to understand the evolution of music sales and how iTunes fits in today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of vinyl and compact discs, song selection was a luxury. The most avid music enthusiasts only bought a handful of albums each year at the store, and most people were relegated to passive listening through the mediocre quality of FM radio. Let’s say that spending $100 a year on music was a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When iTunes launched in 2001, music enthusiasts were given a way to obtain fairly high quality mp3′s from the comfort of their homes. This was an amazing value proposition amidst the controversy of Napster at the time. All of the record labels embraced it, and over the next 12 years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2013/02/06iTunes-Store-Sets-New-Record-with-25-Billion-Songs-Sold.html&quot;&gt;iTunes went on to sell over 25 billion songs&lt;/a&gt;. Even Dr. Dre said, &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.ca/books?id=cf_2PBPP-rEC&amp;#x26;pg=PT500&amp;#x26;lpg=PT500&amp;#x26;dq=Perhaps+the+oddest+meeting+was+when+Dr.+Dre+came+to+visit+Jobs+at+Apple+headquarters.+Jobs+loved+the+Beatles+and+Dylan,+but+he+admitted+that+the+appeal+of+rap+eluded+him.+Now+Jobs+needed+Eminem+and+other+rappers+to+agree+to+be+sold+in+the+iTunes+Store,+so+he+huddled+with+Dr.+Dre,+who+was+Eminem%E2%80%99s+mentor.&amp;#x26;source=bl&amp;#x26;ots=pNPskNZA_i&amp;#x26;sig=YZ8XmtSn5AUiFqhrvFENdt-sfnA&amp;#x26;hl=en&amp;#x26;sa=X&amp;#x26;ei=SPxsU8zJD42ZyAS00IBI&amp;#x26;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;#x26;q=Perhaps%20the%20oddest%20meeting%20was%20when%20Dr.%20Dre%20came%20to%20visit%20Jobs%20at%20Apple%20headquarters.%20Jobs%20loved%20the%20Beatles%20and%20Dylan%2C%20but%20he%20admitted%20that%20the%20appeal%20of%20rap%20eluded%20him.%20Now%20Jobs%20needed%20Eminem%20and%20other%20rappers%20to%20agree%20to%20be%20sold%20in%20the%20iTunes%20Store%2C%20so%20he%20huddled%20with%20Dr.%20Dre%2C%20who%20was%20Eminem%E2%80%99s%20mentor.&amp;#x26;f=false&quot;&gt;“Man, somebody finally got it right”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, in 2014, song selection has become massively ubiquitous. The average music enthusiast has access to millions of songs for free AND legally from streaming services like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soundcloud.com/&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spotify.com/&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. The problem is, at $1.29 per song on iTunes, $100 buys you only 70 songs. This disparity is the reason why the iTunes model no longer makes sense, and the market is yet again ripe for disruption. Music streaming services may deserve a little more attention than we are giving them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the logic above is not enough for you, this graph will not lie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/1*RN9-Z4P2tFLSi9zb4JuTaA.png&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Google Trends (see https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=2004-12-07%202014-07-18&amp;#x26;geo=US&amp;#x26;q=Beats,Spotify,iTunes)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers are already making the switch. Apple knows it too, and this sheds a ray of light on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2014/05/28Apple-to-Acquire-Beats-Music-Beats-Electronics.html&quot;&gt;recent acquisition of Beats Electronics&lt;/a&gt; for $3 billion, which not many people know has it’s own streaming service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/2000/0*AANwlQ2o1hqnqCSw.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Apple acquired Beats Electronics for $3 Billion in May of 2014&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember in 2000 when &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/Rap-artist-sues-Napster,-students/2100-1023_3-239720.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Dre slammed Napster with a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against downloading music online? Man, have we come a long way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This shift in consumer mindset is important for all parties within the music industry to understand. Shortsighted bureaucracy as exhibited in &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisisadynasty.tumblr.com/post/87945465547/brb-deleting-soundcloud&quot;&gt;Kaskade’s SoundCloud account being deleted by Sony Music Entertainment&lt;/a&gt; will not serve anyone well. As music streaming becomes more and more commoditized, the ability of the artists and record labels to depend on album sales will diminish as well. Putting your music online will become less and less about the price tag and more and more about converting listeners into concert ticket buyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, music labels! Steve Jobs isn’t there to pick your shit up this time around. How will the music industry reinvent itself yet again?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why does music sound so good?]]></title><description><![CDATA[What better way to kick off my blog than with one of the most elusive questions of all… Why does music sound so good? Think about it. We…]]></description><link>https://ansonkao.com/blog/why-does-music-sound-good/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ansonkao.com/blog/why-does-music-sound-good/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What better way to kick off my blog than with one of the most elusive questions of all…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why does music sound so good?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it. We know why food tastes good — we need nutrients to live. We know why sex feels good — we have to make babies to procreate. But why does music sound good? It doesn’t seem to contribute to any of nature’s goals whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;md-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./origin-of-music.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Artists rendering of the origin story of music&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even other art forms seem to relate closely with nature. For example, visual art often portrays real scenery and objects in our lives. The aggressive stance designed into sports cars derive their appeal from their resemblance to predatory animals. Even with dance, we can see the similarities with schools of fish moving in perfect synchronicity and the flapping wings of a bird through the skies. But nowhere in nature, not even in the singing of the birds and the chirping of insects, can we find the same musical harmonies and melodies that humans have created with music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do the frequencies of the notes in a C minor chord sound hauntingly good when played together? And why, when we follow that chord with a G major, does the feeling of dominance and pending resolution automatically arise? The impact we humans feel from music seems to be universal. And yet, so arbitrary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mathematics tells us that the ratio between the notes in a major 5th is exactly 3:2, which is an interesting observation. But is that all music is to the human ear? A mathematical curiosity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question is the genesis of my passion for music and the incredible technology that enables it. Much in the same way people wonder why we exist on this planet, I persevere to understand — why does music sound so good?&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>